<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- Marcare un testo plain text di circa 3000 caratteri a piacere.
  Filename: plain_text.xml
  Author: Chiara Bresciani
  Date: 26/06/2021 -->

<!DOCTYPE TEI SYSTEM "tei_all.dtd">

<TEI>

  <teiHeader>

    <fileDesc>

      <titleStmt>
        <title>Dracula</title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Conversione TEI a cura di</resp>
          <name>Chiara Bresciani</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Project Gutenberg's</publisher>
        <date> October, 1995 </date>

        
      </publicationStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Dracula</title>
          <author>Bram Stoker </author>
          <publisher>NEW YORK GROSSET e DUNLAP</publisher>
          <pubPlace> <name>NY </name> </pubPlace>
          <date value="1892-10-14">14 October 1892</date>
          <availability>
                    <p>All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
            <distributor> THE COUNTRY LIFE PRESS
            <pubPlace> GARDEN CITY, NY </pubPlace>
            </distributor>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>

    </fileDesc>

</teiHeader>

  <text xml:lang="en">
  <front>
  <p>
This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere in the United
States and most other parts of the world at no cost and with almost
no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use
it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this
eBook or online at www.gutenberg.org.
  </p> </front>

  <body>
  <div type="chapter">
  <head> CHAPTER I - JONATHAN HARKER’S JOURNAL </head>
  <p>
  <opener> <dateline> 3 May.   —Left <name type="place"> 
Munich </name> at 8:35 P. M.</dateline> </opener>, on 1st May, arriving at <name type="place">Vienna </name> early next morning;
should have arrived at 6:46, but train was an hour late. <distinct>Buda-Pesth</distinct> seems a wonderful place,
from the glimpse which I got of it from the train and the little I could walk through the streets.
I feared to go very far from the station, as we had arrived late and would start as near the correct
time as possible. The impression I had was that we were leaving the West and entering the East;
the most western of splendid bridges over the Danube, which is here of noble width and depth,
took us among the traditions of Turkish rule.
  </p>
<p> We left in pretty good time, and came after nightfall to <name type="place"> Klausenburgh</name>.
Here I stopped for the night at the Hotel Royale.
I had for dinner, or rather supper, a chicken done up some way with red pepper,
which was very good but thirsty. (Mem., get recipe for Mina.)
I asked the waiter, and he said it was called “paprika hendl,” and that, as it was a national dish, I should be able to get it anywhere along the Carpathians.
I found my smattering of German very useful here; indeed,
I don’t know how I should be able to get on without it.
</p>

<p>
Having had some time at my disposal when in <name type="place">London </name>, I had visited the British Museum,
 and made search among the books and maps in the library regarding Transylvania;
it had struck me that some foreknowledge of the country could hardly fail to have
some importance in dealing with a nobleman of that country.
I find that the district he named is in the extreme east of the country,
 just on the borders of three states, <name type="place">Transylvania </name>, <name type="place">Moldavia </name> and Bukovina,
  in the midst of the Carpathian mountains; one of the wildest and least known portions of Europe.
</p>
</div>
</body>
</text> 
</TEI>